Can't sleep?
Tak bisa tidur?
I know a better place to see the stars.
Ada tempat di dekat sini yang lebih bagus untuk melihat bintang.
You want to go there?
Kau mau ke sana?
Okay.
Baik.
-It's so beautiful. -I know. Just like you.
- Sangat indah. - Ya, seperti dirimu.
Drink this.
Minumlah.
I don't want you to get a cold.
Agar kau tak meriang.
I don't want your parents yelling at me for getting you sick.
Nanti aku diminta bertanggung jawab jika kau sakit.
You're not my private doctor. Nobody's going yell at you.
Kau bukan dokter pribadiku. Kau tak perlu bertanggung jawab.
Drink this.
Minumlah.
Coffee is the best aid for a night like this.
Kopi adalah penyelamat terbaik dalam situasi seperti ini.
Especially when you're gazing at the stars.
Terutama saat menatap bintang.
Do you have to drink from the spot where my lips touched the mug?
Kau harus meminumnya di tempat tadi bibirku meminumnya?
It's called an indirect kiss.
Ini disebut sebagai ciuman tak langsung.
Save me a little. I spent so much time brewing it.
Jangan dihabiskan. Sulit membuatnya.
-Can I ask you something? -What's that?
- Bolehkah aku bertanya sesuatu? - Apa itu?
Why are you in a bike gang?
Kenapa kau mau menjadi anggota geng motor?
Initially, I was just curious.
Awalnya, aku penasaran.
I thought people fear them.
Kenapa geng motor terkesan meresahkan masyarakat?
Once I dug deeper, I was hooked.
Setelah aku mencari tahu, ternyata aku terbawa perasaanku.
Because Calderioz is nothing like the stereotype.
Pada kenyataannya, di Calderioz tak seperti itu.
From then on, I tried to change that stigma.
Sejak saat itu, aku amat ingin mengubah pandangan masyarakat.
I'm going to show that bike gangs are not all about parties and trouble.
Karena geng motor tak selalu hanya berhura-hura dan meresahkan.
They can also be about dignity, morals. and helping others.
Namun, merupakan geng yang bermartabat, bermoral,...
I have a big dream about Calz.
Aku memiliki harapan terbesar untuk Calz.
I want to unite all the bike gangs in Jabodetabek and Bandung.
Aku amat ingin menyatukan seluruh geng motor...
I know it's not going to be easy.
Aku tahu itu takkan mudah.
-Come on, let's play a prank on them. -Count me out.
- Ayo, kita ganggu mereka. - Aku tak ikut.
I'm out too. Come on.
Aku juga malas. Ayo.
-Don't worry. I'll back you up. Yes. -Seriously?
- Tenang. Aku akan menemanimu. - Benarkah?
We'd better sleep. Leave them alone. Okay?
Lebih baik kita tidur. Kasihan mereka. Ayo.
I just want to say hello to them, that's all.
Aku hanya mau menyapa mereka.
I'm going to protect them from satan who looks exactly like you.
Aku akan melindungi mereka dari godaan setan terkutuk sepertimu.
What are you doing?
Apa yang kau lakukan?
Go to your tent.
Masuklah.
-Anya, you're invading my space. -No, I'm not.
- Kak Anya, ini tempatku. - Apa?
-Move! -In your dreams!
- Bergeserlah! - Apa, Sel?
If you two keep fighting, we won't be able to sleep.
Bagaimana kita bisa tidur jika kalian...
-Karissa, wake up! -Pocong!
- Karissa, bangun! - Ada pocong!
Aiden?
Aiden?
Ghost!
Ada hantu!
-What happened? -We saw pocong.
- Ada apa? - Tadi ada pocong.
-What are you doing in here? -There's a ghost in our tent.
- Apa yang kau lakukan di sini? - Ada hantu di tendaku.
What's that?
Apa itu?
Moreo! It was you all along!
Kak Moreo! Ternyata dari tadi dirimu!
How could you? You think that's funny?
Kau tega melakukannya. Kau pikir itu lucu?
Where am I?
Aku ada di mana ini?
We caught you.
Sudah ketahuan, Kak.
Just stop it.
Sudahlah.
Laskar made me do it.
Laskar yang menyuruhku.
What? You're alone in this one. I'm going to bed.
Apa? Aku tak ikut terlibat. Aku mau tidur.
Are you kidding me? What if somebody got hurt?
Bagaimana jika tadi ada yang cedera?
Would you still think it's funny?
Kau tetap akan berpikir itu lucu?
-Are you okay, Serra? -Yeah, I'd better go back to sleep.
- Kau tak apa, Serra? - Ya, aku akan kembali tidur.
But, tell Moreo to stop pranking us, nobody's laughing.
Namun, beri tahu Moreo agar tak bercanda seperti itu, tidak lucu.
-He spooked us. -On his behalf, I apologize.
- Dia menakuti kami. - Maafkan dia.
Bye. Good night.
Dah. Selamat malam.
-Babe, don't ever prank me like that. -I will never do that to you.
Jangan pernah bercanda seperti itu kepadaku, Sayang.
-Promise? -I promise.
- Kau berjanji? - Aku berjanji.
-I'd better go now. -Bye.
- Aku akan kembali tidur. - Dah.
Come here.
Kemarilah.
Go to your tent and don't come out for the rest of the night.
Tidurlah dan jangan keluar lagi.
-Sorry! -Good night!
- Maaf! - Selamat malam!
I love you, Selina!
Aku menyayangimu, Selina!
Hello, Lio.
Halo, Kak Lio.
Zea, Aeros' condition last night has become worse.
Zea, kondisi Aeros memburuk semalam.
-How is he now? -He's getting better now.
- Lalu, kini bagaimana? - Sudah membaik.
Where were you last night? My calls couldn't get through.
Kau ke mana semalam? Aku tak bisa menghubungimu.
I went hiking with my schoolmates.
Aku semalam ada acara sekolah.
There was no network coverage on the mountains.
Aku menginap di gunung, maka tak mendapat sinyal.
Zea, don't get carried away with your feelings for Ares.
Zea, jangan terbawa perasaan dengan Ares.
We don't have much time left.
Waktu kita tak banyak
I know if Aeros could speak, he'd tell us who did that to him.
Aku yakin jika Aeros bisa bicara,...
What are you writing? Let me see.
Kau sedang menulis apa? Coba lihat.
-No, Aiden. -Just a peek.
- Jangan, Kak Aiden. - Lihat sedikit.
-Aiden, please. -Let me see.
- Kak Aiden. - Coba lihat.
-I'm just going to peek. -No.
- Sedikit saja. - Kak Aiden.
What's wrong? Did you guys have a fight?
Ada apa? Kalian bertengkar?
What do you think about Ares?
Seperti apa sebenarnya Kak Ares?
He's the best buddy I've ever known.
Ares adalah orang terbaik yang pernah aku kenal.
He's so loyal to the gang.
Dia selalu membela anggota Calderioz.
He never lets anyone down.
Dia tak pernah membiarkan anggota Calderioz kesulitan.
He has done so much for us.
Dia telah melakukan banyak hal untuk kami.
He's the opposite of what he's showing to us,...
Dia tak seperti penampilannya...
being solemn and cold.
yang terlihat menyebalkan dan pendiam.
But deep down, he has gentle heart. That's why we respect him.
Namun, dia sangat perhatian. Jadi, dia dihormati oleh kami.
If we find any traitor,...
Jika ada pengkhianat,...
we'll end him.
kita akan menghabisinya.
Let's go.
Ayo.
Thank you for fighting the bike gang who has been extorting us every day.
Terima kasih sudah mengusir geng motor yang memeras kami setiap hari.
If you didn't come here to save us, we won't have anything left.
Jika tak ada kalian, kami takkan bisa terus berdagang.
-Thank you. -You're welcome.
- Terima kasih. - Sama-sama.
Why are you asking about him?
Kenapa bertanya tentang Ares?
Do you curious about him?
Kau penasaran tentang Ares?
-Show it to him. -What are you talking about?
- Jangan menahan perasaan. - Apa maksudmu?
How about your relationship with Serra?
Bagaimana hubunganmu dengan Serra?
We were talking about Ares, not Serra.
Kita sedang membahas Ares, bukan Serra.
She knows how I feel about her.
Serra tahu bahwa aku masih sangat menyayanginya.
But you know her.
Namun, kau tahu Serra seperti apa.
What if...
Bagaimana...
As her best friend,...
jika kau sebagai perempuan...
can you help me to get back together with her?
membantuku untuk kembali bersamanya?
-Do you have any suggestions? -Let me think.
- Apa kau ada saran? - Apa, ya?
How about a gift that you think she would like?
Bagaimana dengan memberikannya barang yang dia suka?
It doesn't have to be expensive, but it has to be personal.
Walau sederhana, tapi personal.
Okay. Can you help me pick the gift? How about after school?
Baik. Temani aku mencarinya nanti sepulang sekolah.
Okay.
Baik.
Did I hit her with the ball?
Kau terkena bola?
Keep playing.
Lanjutkanlah bermain
Nurse!
Bu!
Lay down.
Berbaringlah.
-It really hurts. -Really?
- Kepalaku terasa amat sakit. - Amat sakit?
I'm going to go and find Miss Dina. She'll know what to do.
Aku akan memanggil Bu Dina. Jadi, kau bisa dirawat.
Please don't go. I just want you to stay with me.
Tidak. Aku mau kau menemaniku di sini.
Are you sure?
Kau sungguh tak apa?
My head hurts. I just want you beside me. Please?
Kepalaku amat sakit. Aku mau ditemani. Temani aku, ya?
I swear, it hurts and I'm dizzy.
Ini sungguh terasa sakit. Aku pusing.
I'm okay now, but please stay here with me.
Kini, sudah tak apa. Namun, aku minta ditemani.
Sit here.
Duduklah di sini.
-I'd better leave since you're okay now. -Where are you going?
- Aku akan pergi. Sudah tak apa? - Kau mau ke mana?
-You don't need me. -Wait! Stay with me! Ares!
- Baiklah jika sudah tak apa. - Tunggu! Temani aku! Ares!
This is Serra's favorite store.
Ini tempat favorit Serra.
Just go and look around.
Lihatlah dulu.
Zea.
Zea.
Found your gift already?
Kau memilih itu, Kak?
Why don't you choose a nice dress, a bag or a hat?
Kenapa tak memilih baju, atau tas, atau topi?
She'll look very beautiful when she wears this.
Serra pasti terlihat amat cantik jika memakai ini.
A sunflower is a symbol of faithfulness.
Bunga matahari melambangkan kesetiaan.
Look.
Lihat.
Yellow represents warmth and happiness.
Warna kuning identik dengan kehangatan dan kebahagiaan.
Those are the things I miss in Serra.
Hal itu sudah tak ada di Serra.
Now she always looks sad, gloomy and angry.
Dia selalu sedih, murung, kesal.
Unlike before.
Tak seperti dulu.
I want her to be happy and cheerful.
Aku mau dia bahagia dan ceria.
I want to be by her side.
Lalu, aku tetap ada di sini.
Waiting for her heart to melt, so she can take me back.
Menunggu hatinya yang hangat menerima cintaku kembali.
Just like a sunflower.
Seperti bunga matahari.
It always faces the sun.
Selalu mengikuti arah matahari bersinar.
What are you doing?
Apa yang kau lakukan?
I just wanted to see how it looks. Don't flatter yourself.
Aku hanya mau melihatnya. Jangan terlalu percaya diri.
I thought...
Aku pikir...
Thank you.
Terima kasih.
(I'm waiting for you in the alley. Come now or else.)
(Aku menunggumu di lorong. Awas jika kau tak datang.)
(Okay.)
(Baik.)
Do want to go to a concert with us? I have five tickets.
Ser, mau ikut nonton? Aku ada lima tiket.
Aiden gave them to me.
Kak Aiden memberikannya kepadaku.
Sorry, I'm not feeling well.
Maaf, Zea. Aku sedang kurang sehat.
But, go ahead and have fun.
Namun, pergilah bersama yang lain.
-This is for you, Ares. -What's that?
- Ini untuk Kak Ares. - Apa itu?
It's okay, I'm giving it to you.
Tak apa, untukmu saja.
-You shouldn't have. -Take it. I made this myself.
- Tidak usah merepotkan diri. - Untukmu. Aku membuatnya sendiri.
Thanks.
Terima kasih.
-Why didn't you come to the alley? -I was busy.
- Kenapa tak datang ke lorong? - Sibuk.
Do you really expect me to come everytime you want me to?
Memang setiap kau mau bertemu denganku, aku harus memenuhinya?
I don't work for you.
Itu merepotkan.
-But you said, "okay". -I did.
- Namun, kau membalas, "Ya". - Tadi.
And now I have better things to do.
Kini, aku ada keperluan lain.
What I said to you earlier no longer applies.
Jadi, aku tak bisa menepati janji.
Sorry for that.
Aku sangat meminta maaf.
(I'm outside.)
(Aku tunggu di luar.)
(I want to tell you something and also want to give you something.)
(Ada yang mau aku bicarakan, dan mau memberikanmu sesuatu.)
(It'll be quick.)
(Sebentar saja.)
A sunflower is a symbol of faithfulness.
Bunga matahari melambangkan kesetiaan.
It always faces the sun.
Karena selalu setia mengikuti arah matahari bersinar.
Look at the color, it's warm and cheerful.
Lihat, warnanya identik dengan kehangatan dan kebahagiaan.
I'm giving you this to represent my faith in you.
Aku memberikanmu ini sebagai simbol harapanku.
I want to see you smile again.
Agar aku bisa melihatmu bahagia kembali.
And I will be faithful to you just like a sunflower.
Lalu, kesetiaanku seperti bunga matahari.
Till your heart melts and you are ready to take me back.
Menunggu kehangatan hatimu untuk menyambut cintaku lagi.
Actually, I asked you to meet me because I wanted to put it on your hair.
Awalnya, aku mau memasangkan langsung penjepit ini di rambutmu.
Wear it, please.
Pakailah penjepit rambutnya.
As a symbol that you want me back too.
Sebagai tanda bahwa kau menerima cintaku lagi.
And I know you will look prettier wearing it.
Aku yakin kau akan terlihat makin manis memakai penjepit rambut ini.
-Thank you for the lunch. -Thanks, Aiden.
- Terima kasih untuk makan siangnya. - Terima kasih, Aiden.
-No problem. -Make it everyday.
- Biasa saja. - Lebih seringlah melakukannya.
I'm collecting rewards from God. I want to go to heaven.
Aku sedang mencari pahala agar bisa masuk ke Surga.
Why don't I hear "amen"? I just paid for everybody's lunch!
Kenapa tak ada, "Amin"? Aku sudah mentraktir kalian!
I'm very happy you eat in my cafeteria.
Aku amat senang kalian makan di kantinku.
So many customers.
Sangat ramai.
Keep the happy spirit. It will help you stay young.
Harus selalu bahagia agar awet muda.
I know. I may be old, but I'm young at heart.
Benar. Walau aku sudah tua, tapi tetap berjiwa muda.
That's the reason I hang with you boys. I want to stay young.
Itu mengapa aku bermain dengan kalian, agar tetap awet muda.
I was once like you, I too belonged to a bike gang.
Aku dulu seperti kalian, bergabung di geng motor.
I looked just like Ares, very handsome.
Seperti Ares, sangat tampan.
Don't compare yourself to Ares. It's like night and day.
Jangan dibandingkan dengan Ares, kalian sangat berbeda.
But it's okay if you compare him to me because I'm as good looking as him.
Namun, tak apa jika aku dengan Ares, sama ketampanannya.
As good looking as a pair of flip-flops maybe.
Wajahmu seperti sandal jepit. Jangan membandingkannya dengan Ares.
You're being delusional.
Astaga, becerminlah.
Hey, Mor, even pregnant women are not allowed to see your face.
Hei, Mor, bahkan wajahmu menjadi pantangan bagi wanita hamil.
What the...
Astaga...
Do you realize that we're in 12th grade now?
Apa kalian sadar bahwa kini kita sudah kelas 12?
I remember my first day in school.
Aku ingat saat pertama kali bersekolah.
I remember Moreo came late, wore the wrong uniform,...
Moreo datang terlambat, salah pakai seragam,...
and he looked terrible.
dan wajahnya terlihat kacau.
And he got punished by the seniors.
Lalu, dihukum oleh kakak kelas.
Admit it, you're the king of tardiness. When will you change?
Mor, kau memang selalu terlambat dari dulu. Kapan kau akan berubah?
I don't think he will.
Dia takkan berubah. Dia saja masih ompong.
Sorry, dude. My tooth is special plug-and-play.
Ini bukan ompong. Namun, gigiku mudah dilepas dan dipasang.
-Put it back on. -Careful, I don't want to lose my tooth.
- Pasang kembali. - Nanti jatuh, bisa menyulitkanku.
-Just put it back on. -Okay.
- Baik.
Why are you discriminating against my tooth?
Kenapa kau melakukan diskriminasi terhadap gigiku.
That's the reality.
Itu kenyataannya.
Then it's been two years since I started dating Karissa.
Berarti sudah dua tahun aku berpacaran dengan Karissa.
She put a spell on you to keep you from cheating on her.
Kau terkena sihir Karissa, maka kau tak bisa berselingkuh.
-I know you want to cheat on her. -Are you crazy? Never!
- Kau pasti mau berselingkuh. - Apa kau sudah gila? Tidak!
Do you remember how romantic you were with Serra?
Apa kau ingat dulu kau amat romantis bersama Serra, Den?
-You were the favorite couple. -See, we're not the only couple.
- Kalian pasangan terfavorit. - Bukan hanya aku.
We're in 12th grade,...
Kita sudah di kelas 12,...
and Mang Oji is one of many people who has witnessed our silliness.
dan Mang Oji salah satu saksi kekonyolan kita.
How about we take a wefie,...
Bagaimana jika kita berfoto,...
and put the printed photo on that board,...
lalu dipajang di sana?
so Mang Oji can see the picture whenever he misses us. Well?
Jadi, saat Mang Oji merindukan kita, dia bisa melihat foto itu.
-Let's do it, man. -Let's go.
- Ayo, aku setuju. - Ayo.
I'm happy I can be in the same picture with you boys, for memory.
Aku merasa terharu kepada kalian. Jadi, ada kenangannya.
-Sit down, Mang Oji. -Sit here.
- Duduk, Mang Oji. - Duduk di sini.
-Look handsome, okay? -I was born handsome.
- Terlihat tampan. - Aku terlahir tampan.
-With or without my tooth? -With, please.
- Dengan atau tanpa gigiku? - Dengan gigimu.
Ready? One, two...
Siap? Satu, dua...
Zea!
Zea!
-Do you know where Serra is? -Serra? I don't know.
- Kau tahu Serra ada di mana? - Serra? Entahlah.
-My pick-up's here. See you. -Are you sure?
- Aku sudah dijemput. Aku pulang dulu. - Benarkah?
-I swear, I haven't seen her. -All right.
- Benar, aku belum melihatnya. - Baiklah.
-I'll go now. Bye. -Take care. Bye.
- Aku pulang dulu. Dah. - Hati-hati. Dah.
-Take care! -Okay!
- Hati-hati! - Baik!
You're going home or going to the club?
Ares, kau pulang atau ke markas Calderioz?
What's wrong with him?
Ada apa dengannya?
Who are you?
Siapa kau?
Pull over!
Pak, menepilah!
Aiden!
Aiden!
Okay. Get up.
Baik. Bangun.
Aiden.
Aiden.
Aiden!
Aiden!
Wake up, Aiden. Look at me.
Bangun, Aiden. Lihat aku.
Aiden, wake up!
Aiden, bangun!
Please.
Aiden, aku mohon.
You have to know that I love you, Serra.
Kau pasti tahu aku menyayangimu, Serra.
Please forgive me.
Maafkan aku.
I failed to make you happy.
Aku belum bisa membahagiakanmu.
-Aiden... -I love you, Serra.
- Aiden... - Aku menyayangimu, Serra.
-Forgive me.
- Maafkan aku.
Wake up, Aiden!
Bangun, Aiden!
Aiden!
Aiden!
♪I believe in second chances For the broken-hearted♪
♪Aku percaya kesempatan kedua Bagi mereka yang patah hati♪
♪Now I can take it for granted Each and every "disregarded"♪
♪Sekarang aku bisa terima Setiap kali "tidak dihargai"♪
♪I fall apart yet I am still right here♪
♪Hatiku hancur Tapi aku masih ada di sini♪
♪But broken heart is hard to heal♪
♪Namun, patah hati sulit disembuhkan♪
♪It kills me Everytime I read between the lines♪
♪Itu menyiksaku Setiap kali aku menyadari maknanya♪
♪Love is divided went undecided♪
♪Cinta yang terbagi Menjadi tidak menentu♪
♪Fade and misguided Just like another broken-hearted♪
♪Sirna dan hilang arah Seperti orang patah hati lainnya♪
♪Now since you've been gone♪
♪Kini sejak kau pergi♪
♪I should carry on♪
♪Aku harus terus melanjutkan hidup♪
♪Cause I'm tired Of writing songs about you♪
♪Karena aku lelah Menulis lagu tentangmu♪
♪I have spent all night♪
♪Aku menghabiskan sepanjang malam♪
♪Just to make this right♪
♪Hanya untuk memperbaikinya♪
♪I can't be somewhere I don't belong♪
♪Aku tak bisa berada Di tempat yang tak menginginkanku♪
♪It's time to move along♪
♪Ini saatnya untuk terus berjalan♪
♪Pain is hardly a secret♪
♪Kesakitan bukan rahasia♪
♪When you bleed to keep it♪
♪Saat sulit sekali menyembunyikannya♪
♪So now I'm the wicked Just not to be addicted?♪
♪Jadi, kini aku menjadi jahat Agar tidak kecanduan?♪
♪Lonely♪
♪Kesepian♪
♪For sure♪
♪Pasti♪
♪But I bet I'm not the only one♪
♪Namun, aku yakin Tak hanya aku yang begini♪
♪Misguided Just like another broken-hearted♪
♪Hilang arah Seperti orang patah hati lainnya♪
♪Now since you've been gone♪
♪Kini sejak kau pergi♪
♪I should carry on♪
♪Aku harus terus melanjutkan hidup♪
♪Cause I'm tired Of writing songs about you♪
♪Karena aku lelah Menulis lagu tentangmu♪
♪I have spent all night♪
♪Aku menghabiskan sepanjang malam♪
♪Just to make this right♪
♪Hanya untuk memperbaikinya♪
♪I can't be somewhere I don't belong♪
♪Aku tak bisa berada Di tempat yang tak menginginkanku♪
♪It's time to move along♪
♪Ini saatnya untuk terus berjalan♪